https://www.healio.com/footer/legal/privacy-policy

The Wyanoke Group Privacy Policy
Updated 12/27/19
Our Privacy Policy
This Privacy Policy ("Privacy Policy") discloses the privacy practices for The Wyanoke Group, SLACK Incorporated, Healio.com, Healio, Healio Strategic Solutions, Healio Live, Vindico Medical Education, or any website within the Healio network. Within this policy, these organizations might sometimes be referred to as "Healio," "We," "Our" or "Us"; users or customers of the website might be referred to as "You" or "Your" or "Their".
Healio.com is committed to protecting the privacy of our visitors and wishes to be transparent in how we handle their personal information. The following privacy policy applies only to information collected on The Wyanoke Group websites or mobile applications where this privacy policy is posted.
Contact Us
If you have any questions or would like more detailed information regarding Healio’s privacy policy, please contact us by email at privacy@wyanokegroup.com.
Information That We Collect
In this section of our Privacy Policy, we discuss the information we may collect about you in connection with your use of Healio. Please note, that in compliance with the General Data Regulation Policy ("GDPR"), if your IP address identifies you as being from the European Union (EU), we will ask you for your consent to collect this information. Additionally, in compliance with the California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA), if you are identified as a visitor from the state of California, we will ask you for your consent to collect this information. This may be asked multiple times in the event that you access Healio on multiple devices (tablet, mobile) or erase your cookie history on any device. If you do not consent, your personal information will not be stored. You will still be able to browse the website, but your experience will not be personalized based on your browsing behavior and certain features of the site may not function as expected. Details of the information we may collect and how it will be utilized can be found below.
Registration. We may request personal information from visitors to our site who are interested in obtaining various products and services from us. This includes registering to become a user of Healio and automatically signing you up for potential e-mail correspondence. Personal information is information that can be used to identify or contact you. It includes but is not limited to: log-in credentials (user name, password), name, postal address, e-mail address, NPI number, year of medical school graduation, and telephone number.
We may also collect other types of information such as profession and professional interests as well as your communication preferences. We will store all personal information in a customer record until you instruct us to remove it from our databases. Registered users of the site are able to control their communication preferences at any time by accessing the "My Account" page.
We may combine information collected about you with information from third-party sources. For example, upon registration, some health care professionals will be matched against the publicly available NPI Registry to append and include their NPI number to their registration profiles.
In addition, this website participates in the Healthcare Communication NetworkSM (the "Network"), and as such has implemented various technologies for universal registration/log-in among all Network member websites. If you would like to understand how this website’s participation in the Network affects your privacy, please click here.
Please note that the Network registration/log-in system may be different from the registration/log-in used by this website for other products and services. To the extent that anything in this privacy policy conflicts with the policy for the Network technologies, the conflict will be resolved in favor of protecting our EU users’ personal information.
Anonymous Users. We may collect information about your usage of Healio whether or not you have registered for Healio. We collect this information through the use of cookies, which are bits of information that a website sends to your computer while you are viewing a webpage. These items may include:
The time and date of your request
The internet address of your computer
The browser and operating system you are using
The webpage that you are viewing
The website that referred you to Healio
Continuing Medical Education (CME, CNE and CE). In many cases, registration is required to take continuing medical educations tests (or CNE or CE) and to claim your completion certificate(s). You will be asked to provide personal information as required by that particular activity. As with registration, personal information is defined as information that can be used to identify or contact you.
Cookies. Healio collects information through a variety of technical methods, including cookies. We collect information through such technology to make our sites more relevant and useful, and to deliver information about products and services to our users. Healio uses third-party marketing services, such as Google, to advertise on third-party websites across the internet. These services use cookies to serve ads to you based on your past visits to Healio. You may opt out of Google’s use of cookies by visiting Google’s Ads Settings. You may opt out of all of Healio’s marketing programs by emailing your name and National Provider Identifier (NPI) number to privacy@wyanokegroup.com. You may learn more about interest-based advertising and opt out of interest-based advertising from members of the Digital Advertising Alliance (DAA) or the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI). In the event that you don’t want to be served ads that are tailored to you, you may "opt out" of many campaigns by going to
https://www.aboutads.info, https://preferences-mgr.truste.com/ or https://www.youronlinechoices.eu. If you decide to opt out, you will continue to be served ads, but they will not be served based on your personal internet activity.
The "Help" function in your web browser explains how to manage cookies while using the internet. As previously noted, some services will not function properly if your browser does not accept cookies.
Comments and Forums. When you post a comment on Healio, your name or username will be displayed. Information that you post will be publicly available and may be used by us and third parties. However, we reserve the right not to post any comments with unsolicited information about medical devices or other products. At no time should Healio be used to provide medical advice to patients.
Mobile Applications (Apps). To access mobile device applications (apps), you may or may not be required to register. We will collect information about you and your use of our apps in the same way we do on our websites. This may or may not include urls that have been clicked on, time on site, and information about the device that you were using when you accessed our site.
Surveys & Polls. Healio may request feedback regarding your use of our services through polls, educational surveys, and other types of market research. We may collect personal information about you when a response is necessary or to fulfill contests, honoraria, giveaways, etc. In surveys that involve an educational component, individuals’ personal information including name, NPI and specialty as well as their responses may be shared with grantors. In other instances, data are collected in aggregate form only.
Widgets. Social media icons, widgets and other sharing buttons may be present on our site. When you consent to using our site, please be aware that these widgets may be connected with third-party websites, such as Facebook or Twitter. These sites track your sharing behaviors and identity (through your social media handles) by utilizing cookies. Your interactions with these sites are administrated by the privacy policies of those third parties. Accessing content that is promoted by TrendMD on Healio is covered by TrendMD’s privacy policy, which monitors usage using primarily anonymized data. For more information on their practices, contact support@trendmd.com.
Why we collect this information
We may use the personal information collected for many purposes, including delivering content, tracking, reporting, marketing, delivering ads and analyzing the traffic patterns on our websites. Information we collect is aggregated into reports that enable us to monitor usage and security. Aggregated and individual usage statistics are distributed within Healio to improve website or service performance and deliver relevant educational and promotional content. Healio may collect and share both aggregated and personally identifiable information tied to IP addresses or cookie information with third parties (including advertisers and institutional subscribers) interested in communicating with you about information or products relevant to your profession.
Personal information such as names, addresses and e-mail addresses may be shared with accredited CME providers in order to award users CME (CNE, CE) credit(s). Names, NPI numbers and specialties of individual users who have interacted with some promotional messages we deliver may be shared with or used with advertisers
and sponsors.
Healio does not endorse and is not responsible for the privacy practices or GDPR-compliance of any third-party websites to which it provides the personal information of its users, although we make our best efforts to collaborate only with those who follow Internet/GDPR best practices.
We reserve the right to review the use of our site by individual user’s accounts associated with 1) attempts to violate the security of our computer networks, 2) activity that degrades the performance of our website, 3) activity that may be related to copyright violation, or 4) if we are required to disclose this information by law.
Healio may also release personal information to third parties: 1) to comply with valid legal requirements such as a law, regulation, search warrant, subpoena, or court order; or 2) in special cases, such as a physical threat to you or others. In the event that we are legally compelled to disclose your personal information to a third party, we will notify you unless doing so would violate the law or court order.
General Linking Information. Please note that some links on Healio, such as advertisements, services, or contextual links may connect to other sites. Any information you disclose on or through those sites is not subject to this privacy policy. Healio does not endorse and is not responsible for the privacy practices or GDPR-compliance of any third-party websites to which we link.
Information Specific to Other Products & Services
For the following items, we will collect personal information that may include but is not limited to your name, address, email, credentials, specialty interests, IP address, date of medical school graduation and credit card information. Braintree Payments and PayPal provide us with an online e-commerce platform that allows you to transmit a credit card number to us with confidence. The Wyanoke Group/Healio does not personally store any of your credit card or PayPal information. We will store all other personal information from the transaction, with your consent.
Depending on your payment method, your data is stored through the Braintree Payments or PayPal data storage and databases behind a firewall. Your information is encrypted through the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI-DSS).
Complementary Book Requests. In the context of a request for a book comp or desk copy, personal information such as the type outlined above may be provided to Healio by you. The information may be used to provide you and/or your institution with product information by e-mail or direct mail that could be useful to faculty and/or students. You will always have the opportunity to unsubscribe from all e-mail correspondence and can notify us if you wish to be taken off of our mailing list.
Paid Content (Newspapers and Journal Subscriptions, Books) In the context of paid content, regardless of type, personal information such as that outlined above may be provided to Healio by you. You reserve the right to rescind your consent for Healio to store your personal information, without incurring financial penalty. Standard return policies will apply.
Single Article Purchases/Single Journal Purchases. Due to the single-use nature of these content types, an e-mail address is required to be submitted and stored in order to make a purchase.
Live Meetings. When you register to attend a live meeting, personal information related to the transaction such as the type outlined above may be provided by you to Healio and then stored (exception: we do not store credit card information). Regardless of how you register for a meeting (online, phone, print form, in person), we will request that all attendees provide consent for us to store personal information so that we can manage your transaction, continue to update you on information relevant to the meeting as well as prepare your pre/post/onsite meeting experiences.
Healio Jobs. Healio Jobs is powered by a third-party firm. Please see their privacy policy to learn more about how your personal information may or may not be used.
Controlling the Use of Your Personal Information
Under GDPR and CCPA, we respect the rights of our EU and California users to obtain information on how we store and access the personal information we hold about them. They may amend and/or delete that personal information at any time. Some of these rights may be subject to some exceptions or limitations. We will respond to the request to exercise these rights within a reasonable timeframe. Other rights Healio users may be eligible for include:
Right of Portability. For Healio users whose IP addresses are located in the EU or the state of California who request to see how their information has been used, whether it is for amending, deleting or for informational purposes, we will provide it to you upon request in an easy-to-read, transmittable format within 30 days of the request.
Unsubscribe/Right to Be Forgotten. If at any time you wish to stop receiving marketing or content communications from us, you may unsubscribe at the bottom of your email(s) or contact Healio at privacy@wyanokegroup.com.
According to your rights under Article 17 of the GDPR, and in compliance with CCPA, if you wish to entirely opt out of having your personal information utilized by our website, you may contact us and we will purge this information from our databases, cease its dissemination and, to the best of our ability, notify all third parties who have been provided with your information that your right to be forgotten and/or erased has been exercised.
Right to Notified of a Breach in Information. To ensure the safety of your personal information on The Wyanoke Group’s/Healio’s website(s) and servers, we have implemented the current appropriate technical, administrative, physical and organizational measures to protect that information from loss, destruction, and unauthorized access, whether accidental or intentional. Since these protections change as technology evolves, we cannot assume any liability in this regard. In the event of a breach in personal information security, Healio will notify affected users within 72 hours of its discovery.
Internal security measures
In order to support its business activities or services, which may include analyzing lists of personal information for behavioral trends and internal emailing of unencrypted personal information (among other actions), only authorized employees of The Wyanoke Group and their subsidiary staff, or our Clients’ authorized staff (who have contractually agreed to keep all information secure) may have access to your personal data. All staff of The Wyanoke Group who have access are required to adhere to staff confidentiality agreements with regard to personal information, which are held on file.
Contact Information for Privacy & Personal Data Inquiries
If you have any questions regarding The Wyanoke Group privacy policy, or would like to exercise your rights regarding your privacy and data as it pertains to this site, please contact us via:
Postal mail:
The Wyanoke Group
Attn: Privacy and Data Protection
6900 Grove Road
Thorofare, NJ
08086 USA
Email:
privacy@wyanokegroup.com
Conclusion
These statements convey the current privacy policy of The Wyanoke Group and Healio. Healio reserves the right to alter this policy at any time without advance notification. Any changes to this privacy policy will be reflected on this webpage. If you have any questions or would like more detailed information regarding Healio’s privacy policy, please contact us by email at privacy@wyanokegroup.com.
